Guide to the First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street records 2011.021
Brooklyn Historical Society
First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street records
1823-2023
Brooklyn Historical Society
First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street
First Baptist Church
Pierrepont Street Baptist Church
2011.021
46.5 Linear Feet in 24 flat boxes, 21 manuscript boxes, 3 oversize flat boxes, and 2 cartons.
The First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street records document the church's activities from its founding in 1823 to its 200th anniversary celebration. Items include registers, member lists, church trustee and committee minutes, building and construction records, and orders of service. Materials from the church's Bible School and choir are also included.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 2011.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
If digital surrogates exist, they should be used in place of the originals whenever possible.
Cassettes and CDs in box 30 folder 6 require additional hardware for access.
Arrangement
Series 1: Church History is arranged in two sub-series by subject. Folders in each sub-series are arranged chronologically.
Series 2: Building and Property Records is arranged in three sub-series by subject. Folders in each sub-series are arranged chronologically.
Series 3: Minutes and Financial Records is arranged in three sub-series by church name. Volumes and folders in each sub-series have been boxed by size and intellectually arranged chronologically.
Series 4: Memberships and Registers is arranged in three sub-series by church name. Volumes and folders in each sub-series have been boxed by size and intellectually arranged chronologically.
Series 5: Music and Choir is arranged chronologically.
Series 6: Bible School is arranged chronologically.
Series 7: Church Publications and Books is arranged in four sub-series by format. Each sub-series is arranged chronologically.
Series 8: Clippings and Scrapbooks is arranged chronologically.
Series 9: Administrative Records and Correspondence is arranged chronologically.
Series 10: Visual Materials is arranged in two sub-series by format. Sub-series 10.1: Photographs and Prints is arranged by subject and size. Sub-series 10.1: Paintings is not arranged.
Series 11: Artifacts is not arranged.
Scope and Contents
The records of the First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street document the church's activities from its founding in 1823 to its 200th anniversary celebration. Many of the church's early documents were kept in a time capsule, which was possibly removed and reinterred over several church buildings, most recently in the cornerstone of Baptist Temple. Items include incorporation documents from First Baptist Church and Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, consolidation documents, early deeds and mortgages, trustee and committee minutes, and publications. According to inventories dated 1880-1894 several items are missing. These documents, the box presumed to be the time capsule, and items concerning various anniversaries celebrating the church's founding are housed in series 1.
The bulk of building and property records concern the Baptist Temple, including construction specifications, utilities, blueprints, and tax information. Items concerning rebuilding the church after a 1917 fire and street updates are held in box 4 folder 8. This series also includes materials collected while applying for landmark status from the New York Landmarks Preservation Commission. Records for other properties held by the church include deeds, mortgages, and correspondence. See series 3 for reports of the building committee.
Minutes from the three churches are housed in series 3 and include notes on the day-to-day operations of the churches, resolutions, committee reports, and information about members, including marriages and baptisms. Vital records also appear in series 4 with lists of members and pew rentals. Loose papers, notes, and correspondence originally housed in these volumes have been left in their original locations. Music and choir minutes are held in series 5 with performance ephemera, sheet music, concert recordings, and organ sales and repair documents. Bible School minutes are held in series 6 with class lists, member lists and financial records.
Church publications include materials printed by or on behalf of Baptist Temple. These include calendars, orders of service, brochures, newsletters, and several books. Clippings are loose and pasted in scrapbooks. Articles cover special events at Baptist Temple and news about church staff and members. Correspondence is mostly incoming, from members, vendors, local groups, and other churches. Letters of dismission to the First Baptist Church and letters from soldiers serving overseas in World War II are also included.
Visual materials include photographs, drawings, postcards, and one painted portrait. Images show members at special events, clergy portraits, the Baptist Temple's interior, and exterior images of the three churches.
Related Materials
Baptist churches of Brooklyn publications and ephemera (1986.013)
First Baptist Church of Williamsburg records (ARC.134)
Greene Avenue Baptist Church records (1985.071)
Long Island Baptist Association records (1978.152)
Young People's Baptist Union of Brooklyn annual reports (1978.152)
Historical
The First Baptist Church was incorporated on October 15, 1823, making it the second Baptist church on Long Island and the first to be incorporated in Brooklyn. The eleven original members appointed Rev. William C. Hawley, who led services in homes and schoolhouses until funds were secured to build a church on Pearl Street, between Concord and Nassau Streets. The congregation's first baptism was held in the East River at the foot of Fulton Street.
Nicknamed Old First, the church opened one of the country's first Sunday schools in 1824. 95 pupils enrolled in the first class, held at a public school at the corner of Adams and Concord Streets. In 1835, the building on Pearl Street was sold to an Episcopal group and the congregation moved to a new, larger building on Nassau Street, installing a Holbrook and Ware organ in 1837.
In 1840, 33 members of First Baptist Church were dismissed to expand the ministry in Brooklyn Heights. This congregation purchased land from the Pierrepont family and built a new church on the corner of Pierrepont and Clinton Streets. First called East Church, the name was soon changed to Pierepont Street Baptist Church. The spelling was later updated to Pierrepont Street Baptist Church. The two churches operated independently until 1873, when they merged to become First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street. First Baptist Church was destroyed by fire earlier that year, requiring the new congregation meet at the church on Pierrepont and Clinton Streets.
The new congregation's 900 members, led by Rev. Jesse B. Thomas, strained the small church building. In 1892 the building was sold to the Brooklyn Savings Bank and construction began on a new building at 360 Schermerhorn Street. During construction, services were temporarily held at the Polytechnic Institute and the Academy of Music. The new church was dedicated in 1895 with seating for 2,000 and an Odell organ. Although the church continued to legally operate as First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, the building was called Baptist Temple. The Bible School operated in the church basement, enrolling 1,328 pupils in 1896.
Baptist Temple was destroyed by fire in 1917. While it was being rebuilt, services were held at the Academy of Music, Central Y.M.C.A., and Hanson Place Church. The new building opened in 1918 with a 4-manual J.W. Steere and Son organ. During the church's 100th anniversary celebration, the mortgage taken out to rebuild Baptist Temple was publicly burned.
In the years following World War II membership declined. By 1955, the church was having financial problems, allowing the organ to fall into disrepair, and by the 1980s neglect left it almost unplayable. A 1991 campaign successfully raised enough money for a full restoration, and in 1995 the church was placed on the National Register of Historic Places and the State Register of Historic Places. Despite these milestones, attendance continued to decline, and by 2003 Baptist Temple had only 40 members.
In 2011, the church changed its name to Recovery House of Worship, and on Easter 2022 to Next Step Community Church. The 2020s saw an increase in attendance, and by 2023, membership was at 200. The church introduced several popular programs to meet community needs, including a soup kitchen, food pantry, children's church, and mother and baby ministry.
First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street; First Baptist Church; Pierrepont Street Baptist Church; Churches -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Sunday schools -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Clergy -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Church buildings -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.) -- Church history; Time capsules; Correspondence; Administrative records; Church records and registers; Black-and-white prints (photographs); Portraits; Paintings (visual works); Choirs (Music) -- New York (State) -- New York; Architectural drawings; Buildings -- New York (State) -- Kings County -- Design and construction; Calendars; Minutes
- Series 1: Church History
  - Sub-series 1.1: Time Capsule
    Scope and Contents
    The items in this sub-series were placed in a time capsule in the cornerstone of Baptist Temple on December 22, 1894. The timecapsule was removed from the cornerstone and additional items added at an unknown date. Materials from First Baptist Church, Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, and First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street are included, as well as documents concerning the church's 1873 consolidation. According to the included inventory, several items are missing.
    - Time Capsule Inventory, 1880-1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, First Baptist Church, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Baptist Tract Magazine, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The American Baptist Magazine, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - The Sailor's Magazine, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Baptist Educational Society Report, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - The Substance of Mrs. Wade's Address to the Ladies of the Baptist Churches in Philadelphia, circa 1834 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hudson River Baptist Association, 1834, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Plaque, First Baptist Church, 1834 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Newspapers, 1834, 1849 (Folder Flat File)
      The Christian Gazette, July 4, 1834; The Religious Herald, August 22, 1834; The Moral Loyeum, September 3, 1834; The New York Recorder, March 21, 1849; Brooklyn Daily Advertiser, April 7, 1849; Brooklyn Daily Eagle, April 7, 1849; The New York Herald, April 7, 1849; Brooklyn Evening Star, April 7, 1849; Morning Courier and New-York Enquirer, April 9, 1849; The New York Journal of Commerce, April 9, 1849; New York Morning Express, April 9, 1849
    - Deeds and Mortgages, 1839-1873 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - American Baptist Home Mission Society, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Brooklyn City Directory, 1848-1849 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American and Foreign Bible Study, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The American National Preacher, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Elections, First Baptist Church, 1871-1873 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, First Baptist Church, 1827-1873 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Mortgages and Bonds, Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, 1839-1859 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Certificate of Incorporation, Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Trustee Minutes with Mortgage Bond, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Members, Possibly Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, 1847 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Olive Branch Baptist Church Announcement, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Members, First Baptist Church, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Clergy, Trustee, and Committee Member List, First Baptist Church, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Deacon Hogan Case Committee, First Baptist Church, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1853-1897 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Treasurer's Account, Ladies Benevolent Society, Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, 1856-1860 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Organ Sale, First Baptist Church, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Treasurer's Annual Report, First Baptist Church, 1858-1869 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Trinity School Property Agreement, Pierrepont Street Baptist Church, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Church Consolidation Documents, 1873-1874 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Trustee Elections, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1874, 1896-1897 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - House Committee, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1873-1900 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Social Committee, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, circa 1875 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bank of New York Safe Contents, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Long Island Baptist Association Minutes, 1874, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Baptist Autumnal Conference, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Treasurer's Report, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Members, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Trustee Minutes and Correspondence, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1895-1897 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Treasurer's Reports, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1895-1897 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Building Committee, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Committee on Dr. Southerton's Resignation, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Music Committee, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Finance Committee, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1896-1900 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Title Insurance Payment, 360 Schermerhorn Street, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Articles of Faith and By-Laws, First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Time Capsule Box (Box 46)
      Box presumably used as time capsule.
  - Sub-series 1.2: Church Histories and Anniversaries
    - Summary of Faith and Practice, 1823 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - South Baptist Church in Brooklyn L.I., 1846 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Copy of 1874 Law Relating to the Union of Churches, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 75th Anniversary Materials, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 90th Anniversary Materials, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 100th Anniversary Materials, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 125th Anniversary Materials, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 125th Anniversary Scrapbook, 1948 (Box 47)
    - 140th Anniversary Materials, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - 150th Anniversary Materials, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - 165th Anniversary Materials, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - 170th Anniversary Materials, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - 175th Anniversary Materials, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - 200th Anniversary Materials, 2023 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - General Church Histories, Typed and Handwritten, circa 1960-1990 (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Series 2: Building and Property Records
  Unless otherwise noted, records in sub-series 2.1 and 2.2 concern the First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street, also known as Baptist Temple. For treasurer minutes, board minutes and reports of the building committee, see series 3. See sub-series 1.1 for most pre-1894 building records.
  - Sub-series 2.1: New York Landmarks Conservancy and National and State Register of Historic Places
    - New York Landmarks Conservancy Materials, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - National and State Register of Historic Places Application, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Common Bond, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      General
      Magazine of the New York Landmarks Conservancy.
    - National and State Register of Historic Places Correspondence and Press Release, 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - National and State Register of Historic Places Clippings, 1993, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - National and State Register of Historic Places Proclamation, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Sub-series 2.2: Church Building and Maintenance Records
    - Construction Agreement, First Baptist Church, 1825 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Insurance, First Baptist Church, 1835-1840 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Insurance Inventory, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Receipts and Invoices, 1893-1896, circa 1920 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Baptist Temple Construction Correspondence, 1892-1898 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Building Specifications, Baptist Temple, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Building Specifications, Baptist Temple, 1894-1930 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Weary and Kramer, Baptist Temple, 1894-1896 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Construction Records, Baptist Temple, 1894-1920 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Inspections, Baptist Temple, 1895-1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Insurance, Baptist Temple, circa 1895-1942 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Maps, 1895-1920 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Taxes, Baptist Temple, 1910, 1957-1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Updates and Repairs, Baptist Temple, 1917-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Memorial Windows, Baptist Temple, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Utilities, Baptist Temple, 1922-1995 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Leases, Baptist Temple, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Blueprint Photocopy, Baptist Temple, 1917 (Folder Flat File)
    - Blueprint, Temple Square, 1931 (Folder Flat File)
  - Sub-series 2.3: Other Properties
    - Church Mortgage Obligations, 1926-1933 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Building Records General Correspondence, 1935-1943 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - 12-18 3rd Avenue and 358-70 Schermerhorn Street, Insurance, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Department of Buildings Resolution, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Sales and Transfers, Various Properties, 1891-1942 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - 637 President Street, 1900-1926 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - 639 President Street, 1906-1910 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 459 State Street, 1915-1933 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - 356 Schermerhorn Street, 1922-1935 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 360 Schermerhorn Street, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 795 Hampton Road, Long Island, 1929-1940 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 469 State Street, 1929-1944 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 461 State Street, 1929-1936 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 469 State Street, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 173 Schermerhorn Street, 1942-1950 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 460 Bergen Street, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Series 3: Minutes and Financial Records
  Loose papers found in pages of bound volumes have been left in their original locations. Choir mintues are housed in series 5, Bible School minutes are housed in series 6. Marriages, baptisms, and member deaths are recorded in early minutes. Additional marriage records are housed in series 4. Membership lists are recorded in later minutes, and can also be found in series 4 and the manuals housed in series 7. The Arthur Norregaard documents include typed and handwritten minutes dating circa 1975-1985.
  - Sub-series 3.1: First Baptist Church
    - Minutes, 1823-1846 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1826-1874 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, Committees, 1844-1849 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Minutes, 1846-1859 (Box 9)
    - Finance Statement, Board of Trustees, 1849 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, 1859-1874 (Box 10)
    - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1859-1874 (Box 11)
    - Ledgers, 1861-1870 (Box 12)
    - Ledgers, 1870-1874 (Box 12)
  - Sub-series 3.2: Pierrepont Street Baptist Church
    - Minutes, 1840-1856 (Box 13)
    - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1840-1859 (Box 14)
    - Clerk Records, 1856-1874 (Box 13)
    - Building Subscriptions, 1858-1865 (Box 12)
  - Sub-series 3.3: First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street
    - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1874-1879 (Box 15)
    - Minutes, 1874-1894 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Clerk Records, 1874-1883 (Box 16)
    - Building Fund, 1874-1880 (Box 11)
    - Building Subscriptions, 1877 (Box 17)
    - Minutes, 1880-1891 (Box 15)
    - Clerk Records, 1883-1896 (Box 17)
    - Minutes, Board of Deacons, 1885-1896 (Box 18)
    - Minutes, Committees, 1891-1993 (Box 8, Folder 11-24)
    - Minutes, 1892-1898 (Box 19)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1893-1977 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Minutes, Building Committee, 1894-1895 (Box 11)
    - Minutes, 1897-1915 (Box 14)
    - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1898-1914 (Box 19)
    - Minutes, 1905, 1919 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1914-1923 (Box 20)
    - Minutes, 1915-1931 (Box 16)
    - Minutes, 1923-1946 (Box 21, Folder 12-19)
    - Minutes, Board of Trustees, 1925-1942 (Box 22)
    - Committees, Resolutions, and Funds, 1929-1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Minutes, 1931-1948 (Box 23)
    - Minutes, Board of Deacons, 1934-2001 (Box 21, Folder 1-10)
    - Minutes, 1940-1941 (Box 20)
    - Minutes, Board of Deaconesses, 1943-1952 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Minutes, 1947-1953 (Box 8, Folder 7-9)
    - Minutes, 1948-1949 (Box 23)
    - Treasurer's Reports, 1950-1954 (Box 17)
    - Minutes, 1965-1971 (Box 22)
    - Arthur Norregaard Documents, 1975-1985 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Minutes, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Series 4: Membership and Registers
  - Sub-series 4.1: First Baptist Church
    - Members, 1823-1970 (Box 9)
    - Members, 1823-1874 (Box 25)
    - Members, 1830-1915 (Box 7)
    - Pew Rental, 1858-1865 (Box 6)
    - Pew Rental, 1866-1870 (Box 26)
    - Pew Rental, 1873-1874 (Box 26)
  - Sub-series 4.2: Pierrepont Street Baptist Church
    - Pew Rental, 1867 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sub-series 4.3: First Baptist Church in Pierrepont Street
    - Members, 1874-1918 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Members, 1902-1979 (Box 18)
    - Member Reports, 1903-1905, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Directories, 1926-1940 (Box 28, Folder 1-5)
    - Marriage Register, 1937-1953 (Box 17)
    - Directories, 1940-1948 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Members Serving in World War II, 1941-1945 (Box 27)
- Series 5: Music and Choir
  - J.H. and C.S. Odell and Co. Organ, 1895-1896 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Programs, 1896-1998 (Box 29, Folder 2-3)
  - Correspondence, 1896, 1945-1997 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Sheet Music, General, 1902-1998 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Clippings and Press Releases, 1904-1942, 1991-1997 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - J.W. Steere and Sons Organ Document Photocopies, 1917, circa 1980 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - J.W. Steere and Sons Organ Receipt and Payment, 1917-1918 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Invoices for Organ Repair, 1921-1933, 1982-1996 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1923-1932 (Box 52)
  - Sheet Music Written by Cornelius Van Rees, 1928-1929 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Baptist Temple Choir Constitution and By-laws, 1930 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Baptist Temple Choir Committee Minutes and Reports, 1942-1955 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Flyers, 1965-2000 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Tickets and Invitations, 1974-1980 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Cassette Orders, 1985, 1994-1995 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - J.W. Steere and Sons Organ Restoration Fund, 1991-1994 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Concert Recordings, 1991-2000 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Cassettes and CDs require additional hardware for access.
  - Personnel, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 7)
- Series 6: Bible School
  - Brooklyn Sunday School Union Constitution, 1845 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1894-1916 (Box 32)
  - A Memory Sketch of Early Sunday School Work, 1896 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Letters and Reports for the Long Island Baptist Association, 1899-1909 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1902-1987 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Secretary's Book, 1903-1916 (Box 33)
    Records number of visitors and class atendees.
  - Treasurer's Reports, 1907-1908, 1956-1958, 1978-1979 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Secretary Reports, 1907-1908, 1957-1959 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Class List, 1910-1917 (Box 33)